Jacob Figueroa

Junior Full Stack Web Developer (651) 434-5212 jacob.r.fig1@gmail.com

Summary

I am a Junior Full Stack Web Developer. My training specialized in everything from building simple web pages to complex web applications. I have worked with relational and non-relational databases and have experience using testing frameworks such as Jest. I recently completed my training and education at the University of Minnesota boot camp, excelling in team-based projects and complex assignments. I am a patient problem-solver who values ongoing professional development and a team member who enjoys challenges.

Experience

Peer Coach, Twin Cities MN - Self-Employed

July 2022 - Current

- Work one on one with peers to help them achieve their goals
- Helping individuals develop critical life skills such as communication, problem-solving, and time management

Planet Juice, Boca Raton FL - Manager

June 2021 - july 2022

- Effectively communicate with team members and customers to problem solve and provide quality service
- Planning and organizing to create a healthy environment for the team and customers

First Impression Group, Eagan MN - *Wide-Format Printing Specialist* August 2019 - March 2020

- Manage time and resources independently and as a team while completing projects
- Install products with efficiency and professionalism for customers

Technical skills

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- MERN (React, Node.js, and Express)
- MySQL
- MongoDB
- Jest

Soft Skills

- Communication
- Teamwork
- Problem-Solving
- Creativity
- Adaptability
- Time Management
- Emotional Intelligence
- Critical Thinking
- Interpersonal Relationships

Links

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/jacobfigueroa95

GitHub: https://github.com/OdeToTheCode

Portfolio Website: https://odetothecode.github.io/Portfolio/

Education

University of Minnesota Boot Camps, Minneapolis - Full Stack Web Development Certificate December 2022 - March2023